Kavitha Annamalai

Chennai, Tamil Nadu kavithaannamalai6_zko@indeedemail.com +91 8754519434

To work with maximum potential in a challenging and dynamic environment, with an opportunity of working with diverse group of people and enhancing professional skills with learning and experience for career growth.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Ops Specialist

Citi Corp services India. Ltd - Chennai, Tamil Nadu May 2020 to Present

- Ø Maintain portfolio accounting and trading systems and interface with all areas of the firm.
- Ø Ensure daily prices and custodial files are implemented on a timely and accurate basis. Perform daily and weekly electronic reconciliation of systems to custodial records.
- Ø Create and verify client performance files, credit card viability and follow up review.
- Ø Resolve trade settlement issues in a timely manner and identify process workflow improvements to enact change.
- Ø Observing the consumers, collecting surveys and then analyzing customer collecting surveys and then collating the customer feedback and data.
- Ø Focus on controlling Roll Forwards and maintaining requisite Normalization in cases assigned
- Ø Maintaining proper Feedback's of each contract and provide the same as and when requested filling and in consultation with panel attorney.
- Ø Maintain MIS of recoveries done and their month/quarter/year end status.
- Ø Conducting periodic reviews and recommending collection settlements & also managing collection legal cases and collection agencies for recoveries.
- Ø Conduct periodic reviews with field team working out strategy to improve productivity, recommending collection settlements to track legal cases for logical closures and maximize recoveries
- Ø Responsible for cash collections / operations / liquidation, cash pick-up, cash delivery, compliance to policies
- Ø Maintenance of POA, LOA C&D Correspondence, functioning in core APC Correspondence and also settlement claim authenticity verification about customer and debt settlement agency, bankruptcy filing or attorney authorization through Pre screening and Post screening of the collections and recoveries Accounts.

Technical Sales Specialist Engineer

CSS Corp - Chennai, Tamil Nadu June 2019 to February 2020

- End-user troubleshooting and Updation of responsive networking feature and make improvised environment for Web page in terms of warranty, update about new products &services, and feature requests.
- · Raise incident tickets, update tickets and escalate and provide closure to tickets in ITSM tool

- Analyzed key metrics to measure network product effectiveness
- Improved process flows and problem resolution by tracking customer interactions and escalation
- Remotely accessing and controlling the user network system for better and clarified version of technical assistance with ease of comfort and relief to customer
- · Liaising with existing clients and prepared tenders, proposals and quotations
- Provided pre-sales and post-sales support and negotiated contracts, terms and conditions and ensured complete adherence to sale target and metrics
- Provided product education and advice catering to customer specified feature and technology and diligently self-update on changing and evolving networking technology as the tech agreement applicable to all type software and network issues on all network devices.
- Consistently reviewing cost and sales performance and documentation of reports and sales literature WORK ACHIEVEMENTS
- Owing to the consistent adherence to the process metrics and coherent achievement of target, was able to get the "Star Performer Award" for three consecutive quarters
- Trained 2 newbies on corporate etiquette and process details for the entire nesting period and also conducted a one month mentoring program for entire team for process development and performance improvement and worked on a project for quality tuning on convention errors and the specific metric scaled from 88% to 96% quality by the end of project

PERSONAL TRAITS

- Ability to manage several assignments simultaneously, meet deadlines
- · Good team player, quick learner, keen observer and deep analyzer undeterred focus on work

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Did certified course on Core and Advanced Java from Apollo Institute of Technology
- Actively participated in the Biggest Female Gender Symbol Formation for the Asian Book of Records at DRBCCC Hindu College.
- Underwent training in "Tele Communication" held at RGM-TTC(BSNL), Chennai-600016
- Participated in a five day workshop and seminar on "Free software" held at IIT Madras, Guindy.
- During the final course of semester in B.E. did internship for "PLC technologies" gaining some hands on experience on logic programming, machine learning and embedded system

Data Analysis Associate

Amazon Development Center July 2016 to January 2019

- Ø Researches and evaluates facts surrounding seller transactions
- \emptyset Takes appropriate action on investigated transactions based on established standard operation procedure and tools
- Ø Documents the actions by providing detailed annotations
- Ø Communicates with external customers via phone or email during the investigation process
- Ø Communicates with internal customers and peers in person, via email, annotations and phone during and following the investigation process
- Ø Understand the issue and make best use of the available resources to resolve it
- Ø Systematically escalate problems or variance in the information to the relevant owners/ teams according to processes and standard

- Ø Communicate with internal and external stakeholders
- Ø Understand performance metrics to create analysis for driving business goals
- Ø Meet predetermined and assigned productivity targets and quality standards
- Ø Assist in list pulling, list management and results monitoring of categorised data spread. Measure and monitor adoption of new features and assisting quicker response and feedback.
- Ø Performed Quality audits and made the annotations of data input for improved response and interface.

Education

Master's in Embedded Systems Technology Engineering

Rajiv Gandhi College of Engineering - Chennai, Tamil Nadu June 2012 to June 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in ECE

DMI College of Engineering - Chennai, Tamil Nadu 2012 to 2016

Skills / IT Skills

- Java
- Javascript
- Python
- C
- C++